<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Secret Unspoken]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog discussing sexual addiction among men]]></description><link>https://secret-unspoken.github.io</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 23:27:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Is it really a problem?]]></title><description><![CDATA[So maybe you are having a private struggle but you are wondering if it is a  real  problem. With so much silence around the issue, and…]]></description><link>https://secret-unspoken.github.io/posts/is-it-really-a-problem/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://secret-unspoken.github.io/posts/is-it-really-a-problem/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;So maybe you are having a private struggle but you are wondering if it is a &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; problem. With so much silence around the issue, and without anyone to share with, it is hard to tell and tough to be honest with ourselves; ultimately it is a question that we answer individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I asked the question for myself a few years ago, I went down this list&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; and had to admit that I was to the point of being stuck: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to stop repeatedly, and being unable to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needing more, or progressing to worse behaviour to get the same effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing a tolerance to the effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the behaviour to manage emotional state. &quot;Medicating&quot; is often the term used when lowering your mood, but the behaviour can also be used to raise your mood. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persisting despite experiencing negative consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to admit that you might be stuck; there is a ton of shame around this issue that keeps men silent and keeps them from seeking help. But when you are stuck you need help, and there is help available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I had settled into a life of acceptance. It wasn&apos;t until a good friend shared his own story of sexual struggle, his drive to get help, and the freedom he was experiencing, that I decided life could be different for me. But it took honesty about my stuckness first. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my hope to inspire you too. I&apos;ll be sharing more of my story soon on how I got help and how you can too. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mark Laaser Ph.D.&lt;/em&gt; (2013) Definitions: Addiction, of LIFE Recovery Guide For Men&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[So what are we hiding and why?]]></title><description><![CDATA[I want to answer the question in the title by explaining the dynamic of the sexual struggle that so many share, and hopefully solidify why…]]></description><link>https://secret-unspoken.github.io/posts/so-what-are-we-hiding-and-why/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://secret-unspoken.github.io/posts/so-what-are-we-hiding-and-why/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I want to answer the question in the title by explaining the dynamic of the sexual struggle that so many share, and hopefully solidify why it ought to be talked about openly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the homepage of the blog, I briefly mention the dynamic between shame, hiding, and the cycle of stuckness men often find themselves in. This is no new thing. Since the earliest records, men have been hiding in response to doing wrong. One only needs to read the record of Adam to know that when he did wrong, he was afraid and so he hid. It can be a terribly frightening thing to risk exposure to those around us when we feel we have done wrong. And that fear and drive to hide can be even more powerful when we not only feel we&apos;ve done wrong, but that we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; wrong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between &lt;em&gt;shame&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;guilt&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Guilt&lt;/em&gt; is about a behaviour, but behaviours can change. &lt;em&gt;Shame&lt;/em&gt; is a belief that touches on &lt;em&gt;who we are&lt;/em&gt;. It is a belief that something is wrong with &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;. Deeper than that, shame is a belief that something is wrong with me that isn&apos;t also wrong with the &lt;em&gt;rest&lt;/em&gt; of us. It is a failure to identify our failures as being part of the common human experience. It is a belief that nobody is as twisted and broken as I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shame... is a belief that nobody is as twisted and broken as I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is no wonder that men&apos;s sexual struggles are being met with silence, false transparency, and inexperience; so many men are still struggling silently, alone, and afraid to seek help. Paradoxically, I have found (and many others) that the making ourselves and our struggles known to other men in a safe community, is leading to less shame, more personal freedom, and stronger community.  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>